{
    "subject":"Current Affairs",
    "topics":
    [
        {
            "topic":"History Nigeria",
            "questions":
            [
                {
                    "question":"Who was the first Governor-General of Lagos colony",
                    "opt1":"Major John Glover",
                    "opt2":"General John Egerton",
                    "opt3":"Mr. H.S. Freeman",
                    "opt4":"Mr. George Washington",
                    "ans":"Mr. H.S. Freeman"
                },
                {
                    "question":"Sir Fredrick Lugard was sworn in as the Governor of the Northern and Southern protectorates in the year",
                    "opt1":"1914",
                    "opt2":"1912",
                    "opt3":"1913",
                    "opt4":"1911",
                    "ans":"1912"
                },

                {
                    "question":"Who named Nigeria",
                    "opt1":"Miss Flora Shaw",
                    "opt2":"Queen Elizabeth",
                    "opt3":"Mary Slessor",
                    "opt4":"Miriam Adebowale",
                    "ans":"Miss Flora Shaw"
                },
                {
                    "question":"Who was the first indigenous Governor-General of Nigeria",
                    "opt1":"Tafawa Balewa",
                    "opt2":"Dr. Nnamdi Azikwe",
                    "opt3":"Dr. Obafemi Awolowo",
                    "opt4":"Engr. Oluseyi Makinde",
                    "ans":"Dr. Nnamdi Azikwe"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The first military Head-of-State was",
                    "opt1":"Gen. Yakubu Gowon",
                    "opt2":"Gen. Mohammadu Buhari",
                    "opt3":"Gen. Sanni Abacha",
                    "opt4":"Gen. Johnson Aguiyi-Ironsi",
                    "ans":"Gen. Johnson Aguiyi-Ironsi"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The most recent amendment to the constitution still used today is the",
                    "opt1":"1988 constitution",
                    "opt2":"1998 constitution",
                    "opt3":"1999 constitution",
                    "opt4":"2002 constitution",
                    "ans":"1999 constitution"
                }
                
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic":"Nigeria Facts",
            "questions":
            [
                {
                    "question":"How many Geo-political zones are in Nigeria",
                    "opt1":"5",
                    "opt2":"6",
                    "opt3":"7",
                    "opt4":"4",
                    "ans":"6"
                },
                {
                    "question":"Benue state's motto is",
                    "opt1":"Food Basket of the Nation",
                    "opt2":"Jewel in the Savanah",
                    "opt3":"Farming is our pride",
                    "opt4":"Gift of the caliphate",
                    "ans":"Food Basket of the Nation"
                },

                {
                    "question":"How many Local Government Areas (L.G.As) do we have in Nigeria",
                    "opt1":"774",
                    "opt2":"568",
                    "opt3":"36",
                    "opt4":"726",
                    "ans":"774"
                },
                {
                    "question":"Yankari Games Reserve is located in",
                    "opt1":"Kano",
                    "opt2":"Zamfara",
                    "opt3":"Bauchi",
                    "opt4":"Oyo",
                    "ans":"Bauchi"
                },
                {
                    "question":"National Museum is located in",
                    "opt1":"Lagos",
                    "opt2":"Osun",
                    "opt3":"Abuja",
                    "opt4":"Bayelsa",
                    "ans":"Lagos"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The capital of Nigeria is",
                    "opt1":"Lagos",
                    "opt2":"Sokoto",
                    "opt3":"Cross river",
                    "opt4":"Abuja",
                    "ans":"Abuja"
                }
                
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic":"World History and Facts",
            "questions":
            [
                {
                    "question":"When was ECOWAS established",
                    "opt1":"May, 1975",
                    "opt2":"January, 1918",
                    "opt3":"April, 1986",
                    "opt4":"August, 1987",
                    "ans":"May, 1975"
                },
                {
                    "question":"What is the full meaning of ICJ",
                    "opt1":"Internal Cardinal Jurisdiction",
                    "opt2":"International Council of Judges",
                    "opt3":"International Court of Justice",
                    "opt4":"International Court of Jamaica",
                    "ans":"International Court of Justice"
                },

                {
                    "question":"The capital of Gambia is",
                    "opt1":"Banjui",
                    "opt2":"Libreville",
                    "opt3":"Egypt",
                    "opt4":"Djibouti",
                    "ans":"Banjui"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The currency spent in Zimbabwe is",
                    "opt1":"Shilling",
                    "opt2":"Dollar",
                    "opt3":"Franc",
                    "opt4":"Naira",
                    "ans":"Dollar"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The language spoken in Ethiopia is",
                    "opt1":"French",
                    "opt2":"English",
                    "opt3":"Ampharic",
                    "opt4":"Spanish",
                    "ans":"Ampharic"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The capital of Yugoslavia is",
                    "opt1":"Carcas",
                    "opt2":"Ankara",
                    "opt3":"Belgrade",
                    "opt4":"Colombo",
                    "ans":"Belgrade"
                }
                
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic":"General Knowledge",
            "questions":
            [
                {
                    "question":"When did the first world war occur",
                    "opt1":"1914 - 1918",
                    "opt2":"1926 - 1932",
                    "opt3":"1856 - 1872",
                    "opt4":"1817 - 1836",
                    "ans":"1914 - 1918"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The smallest continent in the world is",
                    "opt1":"Europe",
                    "opt2":"Australia",
                    "opt3":"Africa",
                    "opt4":"South America",
                    "ans":"Australia"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The Electric Bulb was invented by",
                    "opt1":"Carl Benz",
                    "opt2":"Wills Carner",
                    "opt3":"K. Roentgen",
                    "opt4":"Thomas Edison",
                    "ans":"Thomas Edison"
                },
                {
                    "question":"World Bank was established in",
                    "opt1":"1966",
                    "opt2":"1942",
                    "opt3":"1918",
                    "opt4":"1944",
                    "ans":"1944"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The first world cup was held in",
                    "opt1":"Uruguay",
                    "opt2":"Italy",
                    "opt3":"South Africa",
                    "opt4":"Russia",
                    "ans":"Uruguay"
                },
                {
                    "question":"The largest city in the world is",
                    "opt1":"Manhattan",
                    "opt2":"Ibadan",
                    "opt3":"Tokyo",
                    "opt4":"Argentina",
                    "ans":"Tokyo"
                }
                
            ]
        }
        
    ]
}
